Against an army of Immortals, one warrior must draw first blood.
Blade is a horror, action film directed by Stephen Norrington.
The Daywalker known as "Blade" - a half-vampire, half-mortal man - becomes the
protector of humanity against an underground army of vampires.
Blade, played by Wesley Snipes.
Deacon Frost, played by Stephen Dorff.
Whistler, played by Kris Kristofferson.
Karen, played by N'Bushe Wright.
Quinn, played by Donal Logue.
Dragonetti, played by Udo Kier.
Blade is a 1998 American superhero film  based on
the character from Marvel Comics.
The first installment of the Blade franchise, it was directed
by Stephen Norrington and written by David S.
Wesley Snipes stars as the titular character, with Stephen Dorff, Kris
Kristofferson and N'Bushe Wright in supporting roles.
Blade is a Dhampir, a human with vampire strengths but not
their weaknesses, who fights against vampires.
Blade was released in the United States on August 21, 1998, and was a
commercial success, grossing $70 million at the U.S.
box office, and $131.2 million worldwide.
Despite mixed reviews from film critics, the film
has since garnered a cult following.
It is also hailed as one of Snipes's signature roles.
Blade was noted as a dark superhero film for its time, as
well as being Marvel's first successful film.
It was followed by two sequels, Blade II (2002) and Blade: Trinity
(2004), both written by Goyer, who also directed the latter.
Snipes reprised his role as Blade in the 2024 film Deadpool & Wolverine.
The film explores themes of martial arts, hero,
vampire, superhero, supernatural.
The tone is dark.